

Curriculum Vitae for Anis A. Ayati

Personal information

Address: Spireaveien 12A E-mail: ayati.anis@gmail.com

 0580 Oslo
 Phone: +4799464312

 26.01.1986
 Nationality: Norwegian

Summary

Born:

I work as a Data Scientist at the Production Optimalization Crew in Aker BP's digitalization program "Eureka". I hold a Ph.D. in Fluid Mechanics and a MSc. in Applied Mathematics. Before joining Expert Analytics, I completed a three-year postdoctoral fellowship, which included two international research stays; one year at PUC-Rio, Brazil and six months at Princeton University, USA.

Technical skills

Frameworks Numpy, SciPy, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, Diffpack, AMIDST.

Languages Python, Matlab, C++, Java. Tools Git, Bitbucket, Latex, LabView.

Education

2015	Ph.D. in Fluid Mechanics, Department of Mathematics, University
	of Oslo. Thesis title 'Dynamics of stratified gas-liquid pipe flow'
2008 - 2010	MSc. in Applied Mathematics and Mechanics, Department of
	Mathematics, University of Oslo.
2005 - 2008	BSc. in Physics , Department of Physics, University of Oslo.

Professional experience

2019 – Present **Senior Consultant** at Expert Analytics.

- **Data Scientist** at Aker BP's digitalisation program Eureka". Part of the Production Optimalization team.

expert**analytics**.no

2015 - 2018Postdoctoral Fellow, Department of Mathematics, University of Oslo. - 2018: Visiting researcher, Department of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, Princeton University, USA. - 2017: University Lecturer in Fluid Mechanics, Department of Mathematics, University of Oslo. - 2016: **Visiting researcher**, Department of Mechanical Engineering, PUC-Rio, Brazil. 2015 University Lecturer, Department of Physics, Norwegian University of Life Sciences. 2010 - 2014Ph.D. Research Fellow, Department of Mathematics, University of 20% assistant teacher in Vector Algebra. Student Mentor, TENK (now ENT3R), Faculty of Mathematics and 2006 - 2010Natural Sciences, University of Oslo. 2009 Summer intern, DNV Summer Project 2009, Det Norske Veritas. 2008 Summer intern, Software Development, Forsvarets Forskningsinstitutt.

Languages

Algerian Intermediate
English Fluent
French Fluent
Norwegian Fluent
Portuguese Intermediate
Spanish Basic

Some interests and hobbies

Academic Machine Learning, Fluid Mechanics, Mathematical Programming.

Other Reading, traveling, football, boxing, skiing, fitness.

Extended descriptions of selected projects

Activity Smart Monitoring and Recommender System (SMRS)

Period 02/19 - present Role Co-lead developer

Staffing 2 Volume 100%

Description SMRS is a tool that provides monitoring and recommendation of miti-

gation actions associated with high oil-in-water (oiw) levels in produced water at the Ula offshore platform. SMRS is connected to the Cognite Data Platform and runs a machine-learning backend that provides predictions of oiw levels and categorization of production parameters

according to their historical degree of impact on oiw levels.

expertanalytics.no

Tools Python, Cognite Data Platform, Databricks, Grafana

Activity Development of an aerodynamic model for Vertical-Axis Wind Turbi-

nes

Period 2018 (April-October)
Role Lead developer

Staffing 1 Volume 100%

Description During my six-month research stay at Princeton University, I devel-

oped and implemented a numerical model that is able to accurately predict the aerodynamic performance of vertical-axis wind turbines. The model is an adaptation of the blade element momentum theory

to the vertical-axis configuration.

Tools Matlab, Python, LaTeX

Activity Detailed measurements of waves and turbulence in gas-liquid pipe flow

Period 2010-2018 Role Lead investigator

Staffing 3

Volume 80% -100%

Description In my doctoral and postdoctoral work, I combined a variety experi-

mental methods in multiple experimental campaigns to quantify the dynamics of turbulence and shear-generated interfacial waves. The experiments resulted in large data sets consisting of high-spatial resolution images and various types of electrical signals. The data was subsequently structured and analysed using mathematical tools based on linear algebra, stochastic theory and spectral decomposition. The programming was done in Matlab and C++. Experimental insight was used to optimize Computational Fluid Dynamics simulations.

Collaboration: During my Ph.D. I collaborated with a fellow Ph.D. student, whereas in my postdoctoral period, I've supervised two Ph.D.

student and three MSc. student.

Publications: 21 publications, including peer-reviewed journal papers, conference proceedings and theses. More than 30 talks in conferences and seminars. Reviewer in 4 international peer-reviewed journals and

one international conference.

Tools Matlab, Fortran, C++, ANSYS Fluent, Digiflow, LabView, LaTeX

Activity A framework for risk assessment using Monte Carlo Simulation and

Google Sheets API

Period 2018

Role Lead developer

Staffing 2

Description As a hobby project, I developed a simple risk assessment code con-

sisting of Monte Carlo simulations running on a Python backend and Google Sheets frontend. The project was initiated by a friend of mine who worked for a project management company and was looking for a more elegant solution to the company's Microsoft Excel framework.

expertanalytics.no

Tools Python, Google Sheets

Activity Establishement of a research and education cooperation between Nor-

way and Brazil

Period 2015-2018

Role Project coordinator

 $\begin{array}{ll} \text{Staffing} & 10+ \\ \text{Volume} & 20\% \end{array}$

Description During my research visit at PUC-Rio, I helped establish a research and

edcuation cooperation funded by the Norwegian Research Council and its Brazilian counterpart. During the project duration, 2017-2018, I organized and chaired several workshops, supervised and organized the exchange of Ph.D. and MSc. students and conducted collaborative research with my Brazilian colleagues. In Spring 2017, I was main author of a project application on behalf of the Faculty of Mathematics and Natural Sciences, University of Oslo. The goal of the project is to tie together a large network of Norwegian and Brazilian universities and research institutions through the organization of an annual conference (The November Conference") in Rio de Janeiro. I have acted as coorganizer and session chair in the conference in the period 2016-2018.